Guide to the George Dudley Seymour Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- New Haven City Planning, 1835-1935; Series IV; 8; (16 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, Massachusetts, 1907-1911 (Box 80, Folder 1177)
    - N-O (Box 80, Folder 1178)
    - National Conference on City Planning, 1909-1930 (Box 80, Folder 1179)
    - National Municipal League, 1907-1918, undated (Box 80, Folder 1180)
    - New Haven
      - Maps, 1835-1931 (Box 80, Folder 1181)
      - Trees, 1909, n. d. (Box 80, Folder 1182)
    - New Haven City Improvement Committee
      - General, 1907-1916 (Box 80, Folder 1183)
      - "Preliminary Report Upon the Improvement of the City of New Haven...", 1908 (Box 80, Folder 1184)
    - New Haven Free Public Library, 1907-1916 (Box 80, Folder 1185)
    - New Haven Harbor Development Commission
      - "Harbor Terminal Report", 1921 (Box 81, Folder 1186)
      - Minutes, 1921 October - 1922 December (Box 81, Folder 1187)
    - New Haven Political Equality Club, [ca1907] (Box 81, Folder 1188)
    - New Haven Publicity Club, 1911, undated (Box 81, Folder 1189)
    - Nolen, John, 1908-1915 (Box 81, Folder 1190)
    - Olmsted, Frederick Law, Jr. (Box 81, Folder 1191-1196)
      See also: box 118, folder 5
    - P (Box 81, Folder 1197)
    - Pardee, William S., 1911-1915 (Box 81, Folder 1198)
    - Perry, Frederick L., 1912 (Box 81, Folder 1199)
    - Political cartoons, undated (Box 81, Folder 1200)
    - R (Box 81, Folder 1201)
    - Rice, Frank J., 1910-1915 (Box 81, Folder 1202)
    - Robinson, Charles Mulford, 1907-1910 (Box 81, Folder 1203)
    - S (Box 81, Folder 1204)
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1907-1915 (Box 81, Folder 1205)
    - Strouse, Adler, and Company, 1907-1915 (Box 82, Folder 1206)
    - Studley, John P., 1907-1908 (Box 82, Folder 1207)
    - T (Box 82, Folder 1208)
    - U-V (Box 82, Folder 1209)
    - W-Z (Box 82, Folder 1210)
    - Watrous and Day, 1907-1913 (Box 82, Folder 1211)
    - Welch, Lewis S., 1907-1925 (Box 82, Folder 1212)
      See also: box 31, folders 302-304
    - White, Henry C., 1907-1911 (Box 82, Folder 1213)
    - Woodruff, Rollin S., 1907-1912 (Box 82, Folder 1214)
    - Yale University, 1909-1919 (Box 82, Folder 1215)
  - Letterbooks-scrapbooks
    - New Haven City Improvement
      - (1901) 1907 May - 1909 April (Box 82A, Folder 1-2)
      - 1909 April - 1911 February (Box 82B, Folder 3-4)
      - 1911 February - 1912 May (1911 Oct) (Box 82C, Folder 5)
      - 1911 September - 1912 February (Box 82C, Folder 6)
      - 1912 February - 1913 June (Box 82D, Folder 7-8)
      - 1913 July - 1915 September (Box 82E, Folder 9-10)
        [Index]
      - 1915 September - 1921 July (Box 82-F, Folder 11-12)
      - 1921 September - 1924 April - 1935 (Box 82G, Folder 13-14)
    - New Haven City Improvement Committee
      - 1907 March - 1912 May (Box 82H, Folder 15)
      - "Second Section of Report of New Haven Improvement Commission" pp. 118-272, undated (Box 82H, Folder 16)
    - New Haven Commission on the City Plan
      - 1914 - 1917 (Box 82H, Folder 17)
      - "Secretary's Book", 1917 January - 1925 December (Box 82I, Folder 19)
      - 1917 December - 1924 June (Box 82I, Folder 20)
    - New Haven Harbor Commission, 1913 Dec - 1923 Mar (Box 82J, Folder 21)
    - Old New Haven, 1910-1927 (Box 82J, Folder 22)
- Topical Files, 1684-1945; Series V; 11 linear feet (27 boxes)
  This series contains correspondence, research material, clippings, photographs, printed material, and writings on numerous topics of interest to Seymour. The files are alphabetically arranged by the topic or type of material and include information on antiques, architecture, art, furniture, houses, and individuals.
  - American Federation of Arts, 1914-1918 (Box 83, Folder 1216)
  - American Federation of Labor, 1909-1913 (Box 83, Folder 1217)
  - Anglican Mission, New Cambridge Connecticut, 1897, undated (Box 83, Folder 1218-1219)
  - Antiques
    - General, 1913-1940, n. d. (Box 83, Folder 1220)
    - Schwartz, Morris, 1913-1919 (Box 83, Folder 1221)
    - Stores, 1943 (Box 83, Folder 1222)
  - Architecture
    - General, 1913, 1925-1926 (Box 83, Folder 1223)
    - Thornton, William, 1802-1804, undated (Box 83, Folder 1224)
  - Austin, David (Reverend), 1802-1921, undated (Box 83, Folder 1225)
  - Autographs: Stephens, Alexander; Tennyson, Alfred: Twain, Mark; Washington, Booker T., undated (Box 83, Folder 1226)
  - Automobile accident: letters of sympathy, Circa 1925-1934
    - A-C (Box 83, Folder 1227)
    - D-G (Box 83, Folder 1228)
    - H-M (Box 84, Folder 1229)
    - N-Z (Box 84, Folder 1230)
  - Belcher, Samuel, 1924-1926 (Box 84, Folder 1231)
  - "Better Bulls", 1921-1924 (Box 84, Folder 1232)
  - Biographical essays, 1933, 1938, 1945 (Box 84, Folder 1233)
  - Birchard family: Rodgers, Edna M., 1914-1916 (Box 84, Folder 1234)
  - Bristol (Connecticut) Library, 1905-1906 (Box 84, Folder 1235)
  - Burnap, Daniel
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 1236)
      - Connecticut State Library, 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 1237)
      - Erving, H. W., 1919-1927 (Box 84, Folder 1238)
      - Hoadley, George E., 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 1239)
      - Hyde, Erskine, 1919-1927 (Box 84, Folder 1240)
      - Pitkin, Albert H., 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 1241)
      - Welles, Edwin Stanley, 1919-1920 (Box 84, Folder 1242)
    - Photographs
      - Clocks, undated (Box 84, Folder 1243)
      - Home, undated (Box 84, Folder 1244)
    - Writings
      - Draft, "Daniel Burnap-- Master Clock-Maker 1759-1838", 1927 (Box 84, Folder 1245)
      - Research notes, undated (Box 84, Folder 1246)
  - Burnham, William(Reverend)
    - Correspondence, 1912, 1917 (Box 85, Folder 1247)
    - Articles and research notes, undated (Box 85, Folder 1248)
    - Clippings and photographs, 1912-1913, undated (Box 85, Folder 1249)
  - Bushnell (Cornelius S.) Memorial
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1900-1906, undated (Box 85, Folder 1250)
      - Adams, Herbert, 1904-1906 (Box 85, Folder 1251)
      - Weir, John F., 1894-1906 (Box 85, Folder 1252)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1899-1906 (Box 85, Folder 1253)
  - Caner, Henry
    - Correspondence, 1923-1936 (Box 85, Folder 1254)
    - Article and drafts, 1715, 1722(C.c.), 1925 (Box 85, Folder 1255)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 85, Folder 1256)
  - Church spires, 1925 (Box 85, Folder 1257)
  - Clocks: Connecticut, 1914-1924 (Box 85, Folder 1258)
  - Commission on Sculpture
    - General, 1908-1937 (Box 85, Folder 1259-1261)
    - Shipman, Arthur L, Jr., 1910-1917 (Box 85, Folder 1262)
      See also: box 27, folder 263 See also: box 39, folder 455
  - Connecticut: colonial figures photographs (Box 86, Folder 1263)
  - Connecticut: Courant "Domestic Economy," by Noah Webster, 1817 April 22 (Box 86, Folder 1264)
  - Connecticut Forestry Association, 1906-1909 (Box 86, Folder 1265)
  - Connecticut Tercentenary Committee
    - Correspondence, 1932-1935 (Box 86, Folder 1266-1269)
    - Printed material, 1932-1934 (Box 86, Folder 1270)
  - Coventry, CT: George Washington Bicentennial Celebration (Box 86, Folder 1270A)
  - Cross, Wilbur L.: portrait, 1932-1933 (Box 86, Folder 1271)
  - Deeds, 1883-1943 (Box 86, Folder 1272)
  - Deer: food source, 1915-1917, undated (Box 86, Folder 1273)
  - Dimock, Louis Addison, 1926 (Box 86, Folder 1274)
  - Dissenters' Club, 1911-1937, undated (Box 86, Folder 1275)
  - Doolittle, Amos, 1912-1929, undated (Box 87, Folder 1276)
  - Earle, Ralph, 1935 (Box 87, Folder 1277)
  - Engravers: Abel Buell and Amos Doolittle, 1929, undated (Box 87, Folder 1278)
  - European trips
    - Ephemera, 1908-1911, undated (Box 87, Folder 1279)
    - Letters of introduction, 1909 (Box 87, Folder 1280)
  - Flagg family, 1909-1911, undated (Box 87, Folder 1281)
  - Furniture
    - General, 1783, 1890-1937 (Box 87, Folder 1282-1285)
    - Lists and inventories (Box 87, Folder 1286)
    - Photographs (Box 87, Folder 1287-1288)
  - Garment, Susanna, 1684, 1902-1907 (Box 88, Folder 1289)
  - Gastronomy and punches, 1913-1915, undated (Box 88, Folder 1290)
  - George Washington University
    - General, 1921-1924 (Box 88, Folder 1291)
    - Commencement material, 1879-1881 (Box 88, Folder 1292)
  - Glebe House
    - General, ca1912-1932, undated (Box 88, Folder 1293)
    - Printed material, ca1917-1924, undated (Box 88, Folder 1294)
  - Gould, Joseph F., 1920 (Box 88, Folder 1295)
  - Graduates Club, 1897-1940 (Box 88, Folder 1296)
  - Graves, Henry Solon: photos and misc., undated (Box 88, Folder 1297)
    See also: box 12, folder 114-118 See also: box 60, folder 828-830
  - Harrison, Peter
    - Correspondence, 1912-1925 (Box 88, Folder 1298)
    - Research material and writings, 1916-1926, undated (Box 88, Folder 1299)
  - Hartford (Connecticut) State House, 1913-1921 (Box 88, Folder 1300)
  - Highways and roads, 1914 (Box 88, Folder 1301)
  - Hillhouse, James, 1907-1912, undated (Box 88, Folder 1302)
  - Hoadley, David, 1907-1920 (Box 88, Folder 1303-1304)
  - Hoadley, David(cont'd), 1921-1934, undated (Box 89, Folder 1305-1306)
  - Houses
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1912-1929, 1934 (Box 89, Folder 1308)
      - Appelton, William Sumner, 1913-1916 (Box 89, Folder 1309)
    - Photos
      - Connecticut: general (Box 89, Folder 1310-1313)
      - Connecticut: cities and towns
        - Branford, Canterbury, Clinton, Colchester, Coventry, E. Granby (Box 89, Folder 1314)
        - E. Windsor, Essex, Fairfield, Farmington, and Glastenbury (Box 89, Folder 1315)
        - Guilford, Hamburg, Hamden, Hampton, Hartford, and Killington (Box 90, Folder 1316)
        - Lebanon, Litchfield, Lyme, Madison, Milford, and Monroe (Box 90, Folder 1317)
        - New Haven
          - Bradley(Abraham, J.) house (Box 90, Folder 1318)
          - Bristol(Simeon) house (Box 90, Folder 1319)
          - Churches (Box 90, Folder 1320)
          - Hillhouse(James A.) house, 1925 (Box 90, Folder 1321)
          - Jones(Timothy) house (Box 90, Folder 1322)
          - Lighthouse (Box 90, Folder 1323)
          - New Haven Green (Box 90, Folder 1324)
          - Sargent (J. B.) house (Box 90, Folder 1325)
          - Smith (Nathan) house (Box 90, Folder 1326)
          - Yale campus (Box 90, Folder 1328)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 90, Folder 1329)
        - Norfolk (Box 90, Folder 1329)
        - North Branford: Rose house (Box 90, Folder 1330)
        - North Haven, Norwich, Saybrook, Shelton (Box 90, Folder 1331)
        - Simsbury, Stratford, Waterbury, Wethersfield, and Windsor (Box 90, Folder 1332)
      - Other states
        - Maine, Maryland, New Hampshire, Ohio, Rhode Island, and South Carolina (Box 91, Folder 1333)
      - Unidentified and miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 1334)
    - Writings
  - Houses and churches: photographs and miscellaneous (Box 91, Folder 1337-1338)
  - Hyland-Wildman house, 1916-1917 (Box 91, Folder 1339)
  - Irish players (Box 91, Folder 1340)
  - Isaacs (Ralph) house, Circa 1881-1924 (Box 91, Folder 1341)
  - Leaming, Jeremy (Reverend), 1927-1928 (Box 91, Folder 1342)
  - "Lee Ivy", 1896 (Box 91, Folder 1343)
  - Lee (Thomas) house, 1914, 1929-1933 (Box 91, Folder 1344)
  - Loans, 1913-1916, undated (Box 92, Folder 1345)
  - Lounsbury, Thomas R., 1915 (Box 92, Folder 1346)
  - "Memoirs of an Interloper" (Box 92, Folder 1347-1353)
  - Moki Indians, 1900 (Box 93, Folder 1354-1355)
  - New Haven (Box 93, Folder 1356)
  - New Haven: "A City Asleep--A City Awake," drafts (Box 93, Folder 1357-1358)
  - New Haven Arch of Welcome, 1919 (Box 93, Folder 1359)
  - New Haven Art Musuem, 1906-1907 (Box 93, Folder 1360)
  - New Haven Automobile Club: Traffic Committee, 1920, 1924 (Box 93, Folder 1361)
  - New Haven "Building the City," draft and miscellanea (Box 93, Folder 1362)
  - New Haven charter revision, 1914-1915 (Box 93, Folder 1363)
  - New Haven church restoration: Center Church and Trinity Church, 1909-1914, 1925, undated (Box 94, Folder 1364)
  - New Haven City Hall, 1920-1922 (Box 94, Folder 1365)
  - New Haven City Primer, 1913-1915 (Box 94, Folder 1366)
  - New Haven Defenders' Monument
    - General, 1905-1909 (Box 94, Folder 1367)
    - Clippings, 1907-1911 (Box 94, Folder 1368)
    - Protest before Committee on Appropriations, 1907, undated (Box 94, Folder 1369)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 94, Folder 1370)
  - New Haven East Shore Amusement Company, 1924 (Box 94, Folder 1371)
  - New Haven Elms: photographs (Box 94, Folder 1372)
    See also: box 116, folder 25
  - New Haven Free Public Library
    See also: box 96, folder 1391
    - A-F (Box 94, Folder 1373)
    - Dedication ceremonies (Box 94, Folder 1374)
    - Gilbert, Cass, 1907-1911 (Box 94, Folder 1375)
      See also: box 80, folder 1185
    - H-T (Box 94, Folder 1376)
    - Ives, Mary Elizabeth, 1911 (Box 94, Folder 1377)
    - Watrous, George D., 1906-1911 (Box 95, Folder 1378)
    - Clippings, 1906-1912 (Box 95, Folder 1379)
  - New Haven Green, 1907, 1921 (Box 95, Folder 1380)
  - New Haven harbor
    - General, 1913-1922, undated (Box 95, Folder 1381-1383)
    - Clippings and miscellaneous, 1913-1915, undated (Box 95, Folder 1384)
    - Printed material, 1879-1919, undated (Box 95, Folder 1385)
  - New Haven Improvement Report: letters of acknowledgment, 1931 (Box 96, Folder 1386)
  - New Haven Industrial Exhibition, 1911-1912 (Box 96, Folder 1387)
  - New Haven Industrial Exhibition: printed materials and writings, 1905-1914, undated (Box 96, Folder 1388)
  - New Haven in the field of invention, 1912 (Box 96, Folder 1389)
  - "New Haven in 1850", 1911-1920 (Box 96, Folder 1390)
  - New Haven Ives Memorial Library, 1910 (Box 96, Folder 1391)
  - New Haven Legion Memorial Building, 1922 (Box 96, Folder 1392)
  - New Haven Lighthouse, 1924, 1934 (Box 96, Folder 1393)
  - New Haven marquee question, 1914-1915 (Box 96, Folder 1394)
  - New Haven Mitchell(Donald G.) Memorial Library and Beecher Park Memorial, 1909-1918 (Box 96, Folder 1395)
  - New Haven Municipal Art Commission, 1910-1936 (Box 96, Folder 1396)
  - New Haven Post Office, 1909-1915, undated (Box 96, Folder 1397)
  - New Haven public market, 1912-1915 (Box 96, Folder 1398)
  - New Haven public works of art project, 1934 (Box 96, Folder 1399)
  - New Haven Railroad Station, 1910-1921 (Box 96, Folder 1400)
  - New Haven recreation areas, 1920 (Box 96, Folder 1401)
  - New Haven 'Roll of Honor", 1912-1915 (Box 96, Folder 1402)
  - New Haven Shoreline Park, 1932 (Box 96, Folder 1403)
  - New Haven smoke nuisance, 1912 (Box 96, Folder 1404)
  - New Haven Tercentenary, 1932-1937 (Box 97, Folder 1405)
  - New Haven United Church: fixtures, 1904-1905, undated (Box 97, Folder 1406)
  - New Haven War Memorial, 1919-1920 (Box 97, Folder 1407)
  - New Haven zoning, 1919, undated (Box 97, Folder 1408)
  - New Haven Zoning Commission, 1923 (Box 97, Folder 1409)
  - Nutting, Wallace, 1920-1923 (Box 98, Folder 1410)
  - Order of the "White Rose", [ca1900] (Box 98, Folder 1411)
  - Painting
    - Colonial traditions, 1915, 1919 (Box 98, Folder 1412)
    - "The Green Cloak", 1925-1926 (Box 98, Folder 1413)
  - Pardee, William, 1918-1919 (Box 98, Folder 1414)
  - Patents: (Box 98, Folder 1414)
    See also: box 117 See also: box 118, folder 3
  - Paton, John Allan (Captain): memorial tablet, 1921 (Box 98, Folder 1415)
  - Patterson family, 1888, 1891-1898 (Box 98, Folder 1416-1417)
  - Philippines
    See also: box 24, folder 229 See also: box 116, folder 28
    - Correspondence
      - B-S, 1902-1903 (Box 98, Folder 1418)
      - Seymour, George Dudley, 1902-1903 (Box 98, Folder 1419)
    - Diaries, 1902-1903 (Box 98, Folder 1420)
    - Photographs, 1902-1903 (Box 98, Folder 1421)
    - Writings, 1902-1903 (Box 98, Folder 1422)
  - Presidential campaign literature, 1880, 1884 (Box 98, Folder 1423)
  - Proclamations, 1781, 1835, n. d. (Box 98, Folder 1424-1426)
  - River Farm house, 1912-1913 (Box 99, Folder 1427)
  - Roads in France, "Rest in Locomotion", 1909-1910, undated (Box 99, Folder 1428-1429)
  - Roadside planting in Connecticut, 1909 (Box 99, Folder 1430)
  - Russell,(Parson) house, 1887-1939 (Box 99, Folder 1431)
  - Sargent, John Singer and Riley, James Whitcomb, 1926-1931 (Box 99, Folder 1432)
  - Sculptors, [ca1920-1925] (Box 99, Folder 1433)
  - Seabury, Samuel(Bishop): portrait, 1905-1907 (Box 99, Folder 1434)
  - Seymour, Earle, and Nichols
    - Correspondence: "Nolan bill", 1920-1922 (Box 99, Folder 1435)
    - Financial statements, 1916-1931, 1937-1943 (Box 99, Folder 1436-1441)
    - Papers, 1881-1915 (Box 99, Folder 1442)
  - Shepard, James
    - Correspondence, 1918-1924 (Box 100, Folder 1443)
    - Sketch of Chauncey Jerome, 1914, 1919 (Box 100, Folder 1444)
    - "A History of the Colonial Episcopal Parish of New Cambridge, (Bristol), Conn, 1747," draft (Box 100, Folder 1445-1451)
    - Untitled manuscript: early draft of "A History of the Colonial Episcopal Parish of New Cambridge..." (?) (Box 101, Folder 1452-1454)
  - Silver
    - General, 1905-1929 (Box 102, Folder 1455-1458)
    - Paull, Florence V., 1906 (Box 102, Folder 1459)
    - Society of Arts and Crafts, 1806-1807 (Box 102, Folder 1459)
    - Stone, Arthur J., 1921-1937, undated (Box 102, Folder 1460-1467)
    - Photographs and miscellanea (Box 102, Folder 1468-1469)
  - Society for the Protection of New England Forests, 1915 (Box 103, Folder 1470)
  - Society of the Cincinnati, 1802, 1924-1935, undated (Box 103, Folder 1471)
  - Society of the Colonial Wars: family trees, 1896, undated (Box 103, Folder 1472)
  - Speeches: Yale University, [ca1912-1930] (Box 103, Folder 1473)
  - Tablets
    - General, 1903-1931, undated (Box 103, Folder 1474-1475)
    - Photographs (Box 103, Folder 1476-1478)
    - United Church, 1910-1911 (Box 103, Folder 1479-1482)
  - Taft, William Howard
    See also: box 29, folder 280-285A See also: box 116, folder 25
    - Journal, 1922 (Box 104, Folder 1483)
    - Photographs (Box 104, Folder 1484)
    - Portrait
      - General, 1930-1939 (Box 104, Folder 1485)
      - Adams, Herbert, 1928 (Box 104, Folder 1486)
      - Ipsen, Edith Boyden, 1929-1930 (Box 104, Folder 1487)
      - Ipsen, Ernest Ludwig, 1929-1930 (Box 104, Folder 1488)
      - Juley and Son, 1930 (Box 104, Folder 1489)
      - Learned, Emily Cheney and Henry Barnett, 1929 (Box 104, Folder 1490)
      - Minnigerode, C. Powell, 1930 (Box 104, Folder 1491)
      - Mischler, Wendell W., 1930 (Box 104, Folder 1492)
      - Taft, William Howard, 1929 (Box 104, Folder 1493)
      - Van Devanter, Willis, 1930 (Box 104, Folder 1494)
        See also: box 30, folder 295A
    - Speeches: printed, 1905-1908 (Box 104, Folder 1495)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 104, Folder 1496)
  - Town, Ithiel
    - General, 1890, 1907, 1910-1935, undated (Box 105, Folder 1497-1500)
    - Churches, undated (Box 105, Folder 1501)
    - Photographs (Box 105, Folder 1502)
    - Trinity Church, 1814 (Box 105, Folder 1503)
    - Writings (Box 105, Folder 1504)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1917-1935 (Box 105, Folder 1505)
  - Walpole Society, 1920-1941, undated (Box 105, Folder 1506-1508)
  - Weir, John F.: portrait, 1912-1913 (Box 106, Folder 1509)
  - Welch family, 1903, 1912-1914 (Box 106, Folder 1510)
  - Whitfield(Henry) House and Historic Museum
    - General, 1899, 1907-1935, undated (Box 106, Folder 1511-1514)
    - Printed material and miscellanea (Box 106, Folder 1515)
  - Wickets, 1905, 1909, 1912, 1936, undated (Box 106, Folder 1516)
  - Williams, John (Bishop): statue, 1930 (Box 106, Folder 1517)
  - Wills: George Dudley Seymour, 1929, 1934 (Box 106, Folder 1518)
  - Wills miscellaneous (Box 107, Folder 1519)
  - Women: friends and notable figures, 1892-1932, undated (Box 107, Folder 1520-1521)
  - Woodbridge Congregational Church, 1925-1926 (Box 107, Folder 1522)
  - World War I: relief organizations, 1914-1919 (Box 107, Folder 1523-1525)
  - Writings: George Dudley Seymour
    - Bibliographies, [ca1929] (Box 107, Folder 1526)
    - "Bristol Faces in China and Japan" (Box 107, Folder 1527)
    - "Bristol's Hill-Top Green", 1920 (Box 107, Folder 1528)
    - City Beautiful movement--notes (Box 107, Folder 1529)
    - "Confessions of a Collector" (Box 107, Folder 1530)
    - Connecticut inventors, 1919 (Box 107, Folder 1531)
    - "Cushing and the Abelmarle", 1905 (Box 107, Folder 1532)
    - "The Educational Value of the Manual Side of the Fine and Useful Arts" (Box 107, Folder 1533)
    - Henry Austin and Old Yale Library (Box 107, Folder 1534)
    - "How an Old Colonial Family Lost its Carved Oak Chest" (Box 107, Folder 1535)
    - "Jerome Hayward", 1917 (Box 108, Folder 1536)
    - "The Making of an Old Connecticut Church" (Box 108, Folder 1537)
    - More about Montresor--A New Excursion in Haleana (Box 108, Folder 1538)
    - "Notes on the Meeting of Mr. Taft and Mr. Roosevelt...", 1915 (Box 108, Folder 1539)
    - Patents (Box 108, Folder 1540)
    - "The Salvaging of Architectural Columns", 1921 (Box 108, Folder 1541)
    - "Some Lachrymose Memorials of Hale and Andre at Yale and Tappan", 1931 (Box 108, Folder 1542)
    - "Sons of Liberty" or "Death to Any Person Who Shall Make Use of Any Stamped Papers" (Box 108, Folder 1543)
    - "They Danced on the Table" (Silliman house) (Box 108, Folder 1544)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 108, Folder 1545)
  - Writings: others
    - Stokes, Anson Phelps(?): sermon, 1922 (Box 108, Folder 1546)
    - Taft, William Howard: "Address Before the National Press Club Washington," original typescript (signed), 1914 (Box 108, Folder 1547)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 108, Folder 1548)
  - Yale University
    - Beta Theta Pi House, 1916-1926 (Box 108, Folder 1549)
    - Elizabethan Club, 1915-1922 (Box 108, Folder 1550-1551)
    - Forestry School, 1901-1908 (Box 108, Folder 1552)
    - Harkness Memorial, 1919-1922 (Box 109, Folder 1553)
    - Library and Carnegie swimming pool, 1919-1920 (Box 109, Folder 1554)
    - "Town and Gown" relations, 1909-1920 (Box 109, Folder 1555)
    - Varsity crew, 1900 (Box 109, Folder 1556)
    - Yale Corporation, 1922 (Box 109, Folder 1557)
    - Yale Library: donations, 1931, 1942 (Box 109, Folder 1558)
- Scrapbooks, 1883-1944; Series VI; 7 linear feet (7 boxes)
  This series contains thirty-five(35) volumes of clippings, printed material, invitations, and correspondence arranged in two sections: General and Miscellaneous.
  General contains a group of thirty(30) scrapbooks arranged in rough chronological order from 1937-1944.
  Miscellaneous contains five scrapbooks unrelated to the General section.
  - General
    - 1937 March - 1938 November (Box 110, Folder 1-4)
    - 1938 November - 1939 June (Box 111, Folder 5-9)
    - 1939 - 1940 March (Box 112, Folder 10-14)
    - 1940 March - 1941 May (Box 113, Folder 15-16B)
    - 1941 April - 1942 June (Box 114, Folder 17-20A)
    - 1942 May - 1943 May, 1943 July - December (Box 115, Folder 21-24)
    - 1944 (Box 116, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous
    - 1883-1884, 1915-1925 (Box 116, Folder 26)
    - [ca1886-1888] (Box 116, Folder 27)
    - 1902-1903; Philippine trip (Box 116, Folder 28)
    - 1903-1907 (Box 116, Folder 29)
    - 1934-1938 (Box 116, Folder 30)
- Oversize, Series VII
  - Patent seals (Box 117)
    These six (6) patent seals, approximately six inches in diameter, are often cracked, chipped, and/or incomplete. Three were attached to patent certificates #985 (1871), #1811 (1869), and #1827 (1876).
    See also: box 118, folder 3
  - Architectural drawings (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - New Haven, Connecticut
      - Arch of Welcome (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Bowditch house (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - De Forest house (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - United Church (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - South Coventry, Connecticut
      - Austin, Henry--Nathan Hale Monument, 1846 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Hale, Nathan--birthplace (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Lord house (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Proclamations and certificates